让我们回顾一下我们在这个特定讲座中所涉及的一些重要主题。我们已经
Let's recap some of the important topics we've covered in this particular lecture. We've
谈到了基本的图像形成过程，最简单的情况就是我们所说的
talked about the fundamental image formation process and the simplest case is what we call
“针孔相机”。光线来自光源，在这种情况下，太阳会反射出来
the "Pinhole Camera." Light comes from a light source, in this case the sun, reflects off
在三维物体上的点，那些光线穿过针孔并引起
points on the three dimensional object, those light rays pass through the pin hole and cause
在图像平面上形成非常微弱的倒置图像。
a very faint inverted image to be formed on the image plane.
可以非常简单地解释这种情况的几何形状。它可以用来描述
The geometry of this situation can be very simply explained. It can be described using
类似的三角形，这导致我们三者之间非常简单的关系
similar triangles and that leads us to the very simple relationship here between three
维数世界坐标，大写字母X，大写字母Y，大写字母Z和二维
dimensional world coordinates, capital X, capital Y, capital Z and the two dimensional
图像平面坐标小x和小y。
image plane coordinates little x and little y.
因此，这是从三维到二维的映射或投影
So this is a mapping or a projection from three dimensions down to two dimensions and
这被称为“透视投影”。
this is called "Perspective Projection."
针孔成像模型的一个缺点是许多光线都是
One of the disadvantages of the pinhole imaging model is that a lot of the light rays are
丢失;他们只是碰到了持有针孔的不透明平面。如果我们介绍一个镜头
lost; they simply hit the opaque plane that holds the pinhole. If we introduce a lens
相反，我们能够收集更多离开每个特定点的光线
instead we're able to gather many more of the rays that leave each particular point
在物体上，可以形成更明亮的图像。
on the object and that allows a brighter image to be formed.
透视投影的结果，从三维到下的映射
A consequence of the perspective projection, the mapping from three dimensions down into
二，是不保留一些几何。在这里，我们看到世界上的平行线
two, is that some of the geometry is not preserved. Here we see that parallel lines in the world
不再是图像中的平行线。我们看到世界上有一个大圈子
are no longer parallel lines in the image. We see that a large circle in the world is
不是图像中的圆圈。透视投影只保证这样做，它
not a circle in the image. And perspective projection guarantees only to do this, it
将一条线映射到一条线，但它不一定保持平行，角度是
will map a line to a line, but it doesn't necessarily retain parallelism, angles are
不一定保留，圆锥曲线部分映射到圆锥曲线;这意味着
not necessarily preserved and conic sections are mapped to conic sections; so that means
圆圈可以显示为椭圆，椭圆可以显示为圆形。
that a circle could appear as an ellipse and an ellipse could appear as a circle.
透视投影的一个非常重要的结果是没有独特的逆。
A really important consequence of the perspective projection is that there is no unique inverse.
我们已经失去了一个维度，因此对于特定的图像，存在无限多的可能
We've lost a dimension, so for a particular image there are an infinite number of possible
可能导致该图像的对象。它可能是一个靠近我的小物体
objects that could have caused that image. It could be a small object close to me or
它可能是一个更远的大物体。没有办法，只能从图像几何上得到
it could be a large object further away. There is no way, just from the image geometry that
我们可以告诉你。
we can tell this.
所以在实践中我们使用了一些技巧，这些技巧来自我们成长过程中的经验
So in practice we use a number of tricks that come from our experience from growing up in
一个三维世界，以消除歧义。虽然我们可以欺骗这个。如果我们创造
a three dimensional world, in order to disambiguate this. Though we can trick this. If we create
二维图像;在这里显示为一块街头艺术，它在视网膜上引起
a two dimensional image; shown here as a piece of street art, which causes on the retina
我们的眼睛，与我们从三维世界看到的图像完全相同，
of our eye, exactly the same image as we would get from looking at a three dimensional world,
然后，我们大脑的所有三维解释部分都会启动并导致我们
then all of the three dimensional interpretation part of our brain kicks in and causes us to
感觉，即使理性部分，也将图像解释为三维
feel, to interpret the image as being three dimensional even though the rational part
我们的大脑知道这是一块平坦的街头艺术。印象还是很的，
of our brain knows that this is a piece of flat street art. The impression is still very,
非常生动。
very vivid.
另一种我们可以看到没有唯一逆的结果的方法是在
Another way we can look at the consequence of there being no unique inverse is in an
像这样的错觉，因为克里斯是一个全尺寸的人，但因为他站着
illusion like this and it's because Chris is a full size person but because he's standing
更远的地方，他看起来更小，虽然最初我们对我们感到惊讶
further away he appears to be smaller and although initially we're surprised when we
再看看我们理解三维的大脑的理性部分
look at that, again the rational part of our brain that understands the three dimensional
世界开始并说：“好吧，实际上我们会假设他是一个全尺寸的人，
world kicks in and says "Okay, actually we will assume that he is a full size person,
因此，他必须离得更远。“
he therefore must be further away."